COVID-19 Pandemic Collection MS269
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
COVID-19 Pandemic Collection
circa 1949 -- 1953, 2003, 2020 -- 2021
2020
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
MS269
166 Digital Object(s) Of the 166 digital objects, one digital object comprises 98 files.
11.7 Gigabytes
483 Web sites
The novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2, which causes the disease COVID-19 in infected patients, was identified in late 2019 in Wuhan, China. By February 2020, the virus had spread outside of China into Europe and other areas of the world, causing stay-at-home orders to be implemented, and schools and non-essential businesses to close. On March 10, 2020, Tufts University announced that all classes would be moved online, and that all on-campus facilities would be closed for the remainder of the semester, requiring students to move out of dormitories by the end of the week. The COVID-19 Pandemic Collection contains material documenting COVID-19 and its impact on faculty, staff, and students at Tufts University.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ana Sophia Ascota, 2020, MS-2020-062; Jeffrey Rawitsch, 2020, accession MS-2020-063; Lauren Soherr, 2020, accession MS-2020-065; Jake Zaslav, 2020, MS-2020-067; Luke Allocco, 2020, accession MS-2020-068; Silvia Bottinelli, 2020, accession MS-2020-069; Annie Ziwen Yin, 2020, MS-2021-001; Elizabeth Mainiero, 2020, MS-2021-002; Sarah Wiener, 2020, MS-2021-003; Tony Monaco, 2020, UA-2021-005; John Wescott, 2020, UA-2021-002.
Biographical / Historical
The novel coronavirus SARS-CoV-2, which causes the disease COVID-19 in infected patients, was identified in late 2019 in Wuhan, China. It was known for being highly contagious, as well as for causing fever and respiratory symptoms in infected patients. By February 2020, the virus had spread outside of China into Europe and other areas of the world, causing stay-at-home orders to be implemented, and schools and non-essential businesses to close. In the United States, the closure of most businesses caused a rapid spike in unemployment across the country.
On March 10, 2020, Tufts University announced that all classes would be moved online, and that all on-campus facilities would be closed for the remainder of the semester, requiring students to move out of dormitories by the end of the week. Commencement for graduating students was subsequently moved online, with a later in-person date to be announced when it was safe to do so. The university made changes to its academic grading system, with faculty voting to allow undergraduate students to opt-in to a pass/fail grading system for any class regardless of any requirements. On March 15, 2020, the university announced that all staff would begin working remotely by March 17, 2020 unless their work required them to report to campus in order to maintain operational and academic continuity. The university additionally opened up its residence halls to local hospitals to house patients, first responders, and essential workers.
Scope and Contents
The COVID-19 Pandemic Collection contains material documenting COVID-19 and its impact on faculty, staff, and students at Tufts University. Photographs, videos, diaries, written reflections, and web captures document the Tufts Medford campus, faculty and staff work, and how students' lives changes a result of disruption to the Spring 2020 semester. The vast majority of materials in this collection were created in 2020. There are a few items digitized in 2020, for which the originals date to 1949 -- 1953 and 2003, documenting the life of alumnus Vincent Maniero.
University history; Student life
- COVID-19 pandemic collection, circa 1949 -- 1953, 2003, 2020; 2020; MS269.000001; 11.7 Gigabytes; 166 Digital Object(s) Of the 166 digital objects, one digital object comprises 98 files.; 1 Web sites
  Arrangement
  This collection is arranged chronologically in the order of accession.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains material documenting COVID-19 and its impact on faculty, staff, and students at Tufts University.
  - Tufts campus, graduation, and claps for essential workers photographs and videos, 2020 March -- 2020 May; MS269.000039; 2.4 Gigabytes; 73 Digital Object(s)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Open for research.
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Transferred by Ana Sophia Acosta, April and June 2020, accession number MS-2020-062.
    Photos and videos of the Tufts campus and New York City during the COVID-19 pandemic. This material includes photos and videos of the Illumination Ceremony, a Tufts tradition typically celebrated on the eve of Commencement; students moving out of campus housing; an unofficial graduation ceremony; and New York City residents clapping for essential workers. Item-level description of the photographs and videos was provided by Ana Sophia Acosta.
    - Illumination Ceremony video clips, 2020 March; MS269.000040; 730.4 Megabytes; 6 Digital Object(s)
      Video clips of an impromptu Illumination Ceremony.
      - Senior Ross Hamilton speaking at the Illumination Ceremony, 2020 March 11; MS269.000041; 193.2 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Senior Ross Hamilton speaking at the Illumination Ceremony.
      - Students lighting candles at the Illumination Ceremony, 2020 March 11; MS269.000042; 93.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Students passing the candle flame at the Illumination Ceremony.
      - Students singing at the Illumination Ceremony, 2020 March 11; MS269.000043; 268.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Tufts seniors gathered for an impromptu Illumination Ceremony following Tufts' decision to suspend all in-person classes.
      - The Ladies of Essence singing at the Illumination Ceremony, 2020 March 11; MS269.000044; 346.8 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
        The Ladies of Essence sing at the Illumination Ceremony.
      - Seniors singing "This Little Light of Mine" at the Illumination Ceremony, 2020 March 11; MS269.000045; 87.8 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Seniors singing "This Little Light of Mine" at the Illumination Ceremony.
      - Video of the Illumination Ceremony created for The Tufts Daily, 2020 March 11; MS269.000046; 87.4 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Video of the Illumination Ceremony created for The Tufts Daily.
    - Last days at Tufts video clips, 2020 March; MS269.000047; 491.6 Megabytes; 23 Digital Object(s)
      Video clips of students' last days on campus at the beginning of the COVID-19 pandemic.
      - Seniors react to Tufts' decision to suspend all in-person classes, 2020 March 10; MS269.000048; 45.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Seniors react to Tufts' decision to suspend all in-person classes, which would also end their time in college together.
      - Students leaving a lecture hall on campus, 2020 March 12; MS269.000049; 7.2 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Nearly empty classroom on the last day of in-person classes.
      - Students in the Mayer Campus Center building, 2020 March 12; MS269.000050; 4.1 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Nearly empty Campus Center Commons on the last day of in-person classes.
      - Students in the Mayer Campus Center building, 2020 March 12; MS269.000051; 7.2 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Nearly empty Hotung café on the last day of in-person classes.
      - Serena Montiero moving an office chair across campus, 2020 March 12; MS269.000052; 61.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Specialty Recycling Intern Serena Montiero skating desk chair to donation station.
      - Tufts Cannon painted with messages from the Class of 2020, 2020 March 12; MS269.000053; 23.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Tufts Canon painted with "Corona 2020."
      - Student rearranging boxes for storage, 2020 March 12; MS269.000054; 45.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Specialty Recycling Intern Serena Montiero moving boxes in 550 Boston Ave to make space for student move out donations.
      - Student walking through an empty campus building, 2020 March 12; MS269.000055; 52.9 Megabytes
        550 Boston Ave space where student move out donations would be sent.
      - Student walking through campus during the day, 2020 March 13; MS269.000056; 21.9 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Empty Academic Quad.
      - Flags blowing in the wind on campus, 2020 March 13; MS269.000057; 8.9 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - Students walking through campus during the day, 2020 March 13; MS269.000058; 10.2 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Nearly empty Academic Quad.
      - Sunrise over Tufts Community Housing, 2020 March 14; MS269.000059; 9.9 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Sunrise over Tufts CoHo housing.
      - Academic Quad at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000060; 11.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Academic Quad at sunrise.
      - Tisch Roof at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000061; 15.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Tisch Roof at sunrise.
      - Students on Tisch roof at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000062; 13.8 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Students on Tisch Roof at sunrise.
      - Aidan Kelliher on Tisch roof at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000063; 21.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Aidan Kelliher on Tisch Roof at sunrise.
      - Academic Quad flags at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000064; 13.2 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Academic Quad flags at sunrise.
      - Academic Quad at sunrise, 2020 March 14; MS269.000065; 49.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - Student packing up their bedroom to move out, 2020 March 14; MS269.000066; 10.9 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Student bedroom during move out.
      - People loading cars during move out, 2020 March 14; MS269.000067; 8.8 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Student's family packing car during move out.
      - Students video chatting with each other outside an apartment building, 2020 March 14; MS269.000068; 21.1 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Serena Montiero, Elyssa Anneser, and Ana Sophia Acosta on FaceTime with Jake Zaslav after he returned home.
      - Student walking through an empty bedroom after moving out, 2020 March 14; MS269.000069; 16.6 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Empty student bedroom during move out.
      - Student walking through an empty apartment after moving out, 2020 March 14; MS269.000070; 21.8 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Empty student apartment during move out.
    - New York City claps for essential workers video clips, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000071; 1 Gigabytes; 12 Digital Object(s)
      Video clips of New York City residents clapping for essential workers.
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000072; 61.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        7:00-7:02 clap for essential workers during New York City's Stay at Home Orders.
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000073; 64.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000074; 328.9 Megabytes; 2 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000075; 52.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000076; 164.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000077; 13.9 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000078; 73.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000079; 40.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000080; 54.5 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000081; 51.1 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - New York City claps for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000082; 32.5 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - Compilation of video clips of New York City residents clapping for essential workers, 2020 March -- 2020 April; MS269.000083; 89.6 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Compilation of clips of the nightly 7:00-7:02 clap for essential workers outside Ana Sophia Acosta's window.
    - Graduation videos and photographs, 2020 May; MS269.000084; 154.2 Megabytes; 31 Digital Object(s)
      Photographs and video clips of graduating students celebrating Commencement during the COVID-19 pandemic.
      - Ana Sophia Acosta celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000085; 6.2 Megabytes
      - Ana Sophia Acosta celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000086; 5.8 Megabytes
      - Ana Sophia Acosta celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000087; 7.8 Megabytes
      - Ana Sophia Acosta and friends celebrate graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000088; 9.7 Megabytes
        Students Ana Sophia Acosta, Anna Champion, Emma Wolfe, Elyssa Annesser, Julia Devlin, and Serena Montiero celebrating graduation.
      - Ana Sophia Acosta and friends celebrate graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000089; 9.8 Megabytes
      - Ana Sophia Acosta and friends celebrate graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000090; 6.4 Megabytes
      - Emma Wolfe celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000091; 5.6 Megabytes
        Student Emma Wolfe celebrating graduation.
      - Students posing in front of Jumbo statue, 2020 May 16; MS269.000092; 1.2 Megabytes
        Students Ana Sophia Acosta, Anna Champion, Jay Mirecki, Elyssa Anneser, and Emma Wolfe.
      - Students wearing masks posing outside Downeast Cider House, 2020 May 16; MS269.000093; 3 Megabytes
        Students Anna Champion, Jay Mirecki, Emma Wolfe, and Elyssa Annesser outside of Downeast Cider House after their graduation celebration.
      - Emma Wolfe celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000094; 5.4 Megabytes
      - Julia Devlin celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000095; 5.6 Megabytes
        Student Julia Devlin celebrating graduation.
      - Students in caps and gowns walking down Bromfield Road, 2020 May 17; MS269.000096; 1.8 Megabytes
        Students walking down Bromfield Road for a student organized graduation ceremony.
      - Elyssa Anneser celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000097; 6 Megabytes
        Student Elyssa Anneser celebrating graduation.
      - Tufts Cannon painted for 2020 commencement ceremony, 2020 May 16; MS269.000098; 1.9 Megabytes
        Tufts Cannon painted for 2020 Commencement ceremony.
      - Tufts Cannon painted for 2020 commencement ceremony, 2020 May 16; MS269.000099; 2.2 Megabytes
      - Elyssa Anneser wearing a mask on Tisch Library roof on the night after graduaiton, 2020 May 17; MS269.000100; 1.7 Megabytes
        Student Elyssa Anneser wearing a mask on Tisch Library roof on the night after graduation.
      - Elyssa Anneser celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000101; 5.7 Megabytes
      - Serena Montiero celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000102; 6.2 Megabytes
        Student Serena Montiero celebrating graduation.
      - Serena Montiero's graduation cap, 2020 May 16; MS269.000103; 5.2 Megabytes
        Student Serena Montiero's graduation cap.
      - Serena Montiero celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000104; 5.9 Megabytes
      - Anna Champion celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000105; 7.7 Megabytes
        Student Anna Champion celebrating graduation.
      - Anna Champion celebrating graduation, 2020 May 16; MS269.000106; 5.7 Megabytes
      - Serena Montiero wearing mask posing next to Colossal AcornHead sculpture, 2020 May 16; MS269.000107; 9.5 Megabytes
      - Emma Wolfe and Anna Champion blowing kisses at each other on Tisch Library roof, 2020 May 16; MS269.000108; 6.8 Megabytes
        Students Emma Wolfe and Anna Champion on the Tisch Library roof.
      - Julia Devlin and Elyssa Anneser reaching towards each other standing on Tisch Library roof, 2020 May 16; MS269.000109; 6.4 Megabytes
        Students Julia Devlin and Elyssa Anneser on the Tisch Library roof.
      - Serena Montiero and Elyssa Anneser reaching towards each other standing on Tisch Library roof, 2020 May 16; MS269.000110; 6.4 Megabytes
        Students Serena Montiero and Elyssa Anneser on the Tisch Library roof.
      - Group of students wearing masks on the steps of their off-campus apartment, 2020 May 16; MS269.000111; 8.6 Megabytes
        Students Anna Champion, Emma Wolfe, Julia Devlin, and Elyssa Anneser on the steps of their off-campus apartment before taking graduation pictures.
      - Students watching the Tufts graduation video while wearing masks, 2020 May 17; MS269.000112; 15.5 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Elyssa Annesser, Ana Sophia Acosta, and Emma Wolfe watching the Tufts graduation video while wearing masks.
      - Students watching the Tufts graduation video while wearing masks, 2020 May 17; MS269.000113; 25.3 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
      - Graduating seniors walking down Bromfield Road for Bromfield Road Graduation, 2020 May 17; MS269.000114; 6.5 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Graduating seniors walking down Bromfield Road for "Bromfield Road Graduation." Students living on the street gathered to socially distant walk down the street in their graduation attire while neighbors cheered from their porches.
      - Tufts Canon painted for the Class of 2020, 2020 May 17; MS269.000115; 3.8 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
        Tufts Canon painted for the Class of 2020.
      - Students in caps and gowns walking down Bromfield Road, 2020 May 17; MS269.000123; 7.7 Megabytes; 1 Minutes
  - COVID Funk lyrics and recordings, 2020 March 26; MS269.000002; 14.6 Megabytes; 2 Digital Object(s)
    This file contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list.
    Transferred by Jeffrey Rawitsch, April 2020, accession number MS-2020-063.
    Lyric sheet and audio recording created by Jeffrey Rawitsch, Granoff Music Center manager, in Arlington, Massachusetts as a public service announcement about COVID-19. Set to "Uptown Funk" as recorded by Mark Ronson, featuring Bruno Mars.
    - COVID Funk lyrics, 2020 March 26; MS269.000003; 29 Kilobytes
    - COVID Funk audio recordings, 2020 March 26; MS269.000004; 14.6 Megabytes; 1 Digital Object(s) 1 digital object comprising two files.
      Files available upon request. Please contact DCA for access.
  - Quarantine video diary, 2020 March -- April; MS269.000005; 787 Megabytes; 3 Digital Object(s)
    Transferred by Lauren Soherr, May 2020, accession number MS-2020-065.
    Video diary kept by Lauren Soherr during her fourteen day self-isolation after returning from Tufts to her home in Albuquerque, New Mexico.
    - Quarantine day one video, 2020 March 16; MS269.000006; 278 Megabytes; 5 Minutes
    - Quarantine day three video, 2020 March 18; MS269.000007; 192 Megabytes; 3 Minutes
    - Corona update video, 2020 April 08; MS269.000008; 317 Megabytes; 10 Minutes
  - Jake Zaslav interview with Umbrella Pine, 2020 March -- 2020 July; MS269.000116; 245 Megabytes; 2 Digital Object(s)
    Transferred by Jake Zaslav, April and July 2020, accession number MS-2020-067.
    "A Conversation with Umbrella Pine" is an interview-based documentary from director Jake Zaslav (Arts and Sciences, 2020) with Umbrella Pine, Magdalena Abrego and Allison Burik's contemporary improvisation duo. Produced for Professor Natalie Minik's course, "FMS-037 Documentary History and Practice," the film documents the challenges performing musicians faced during the COVID-19 pandemic.
    - A conversation with Umbrella Pine, 2020 March; MS269.000117; 245 Megabytes; 4 Minutes
      File available upon request. Please contact DCA for access.
    - Description of project, 2020 July; MS269.000118; 11 Kilobytes
  - Tufts campus photographs and COVID-19 reflection, 2020 March -- June; MS269.000009; 143.1 Megabytes; 27 Digital Object(s)
    Transferred by Luke Allocco, June 2020, accession number MS-2020-068.
    Personal reflection detailing Luke Allocco's experiences following the announcement of the University's closure in March 2020 and photographs of various campus locations. Item-level description of the photographs was provided by the donor.
    - Copies of the Tufts Daily, 2020 March 11; MS269.000010; 5.1 Megabytes
      The Daily's March 11, 2020 issue.
    - Hotung Cafe televisions, 2020 March 11; MS269.000011; 5.2 Megabytes
      Blurry, but coronavirus news on the TVs in Hotung Cafe. It was becoming harder to escape news of the pandemic.
    - Tufts Daily in Campus Center foyer, 2020 March 11; MS269.000012; 6.1 Megabytes
      The stack of Dailies on their rack in the Campus Center foyer.
    - Tisch Library closing sign, 2020 March 11; MS269.000013; 5.1 Megabytes
    - Tisch Library closing sign, 2020 March 11; MS269.000014; 5.2 Megabytes
      Notice on the front entrance to Tisch Library, March 11, 2020.
    - Tufts Cannon, 2020 March 11; MS269.000015; 9.6 Megabytes
    - Ambulance on Tufts campus, 2020 March 11; MS269.000016; 9.4 Megabytes
      As the news of a COVID-positive student on campus spread, it seemed like I should capture this image of an ambulance responding to a call on campus, even though nothing came of it.
    - Tufts Cannon, 2020 March 11; MS269.000017; 7.6 Megabytes
      Text on Cannon reads "Run like hell."
    - Tufts Cannon, 2020 March 11; MS269.000018; 7.9 Megabytes
      Cannon the morning after the university's announcement that classes would be suspended.
    - Fire truck on Tufts campus, 2020 March 11; MS269.000019; 7.9 Megabytes
    - Ambulance outside of Dewick Hall, 2020 March 11; MS269.000020; 8.8 Megabytes
      That ambulance from earlier ended up outside Dewick.
    - Spring Fling sign in Campus Center, 2020 March 11; MS269.000021; 7.2 Megabytes
      Same issue as the table tents in Tisch. Felt weird passing this advertisement in the campus center not knowing if Spring Fling would happen.
    - Empty Tisch Library, 2020 March 11; MS269.000022; 5.2 Megabytes
      Empty Tisch Library, March 11, 2020.
    - Empty Tisch Library, 2020 March 11; MS269.000023; 4.3 Megabytes
      Another shot of the empty Tisch Library, March 11, 2020. Going to the library seemed to be the last thing on students' minds after the university's announcement.
    - Empty Tisch Library, 2020 March 11; MS269.000024; 4.9 Megabytes
      An empty Tisch Library, taken during open block, March 11, 2020.
    - Senior Week table tents in Tisch Library, 2020 March 11; MS269.000025; 5.4 Megabytes
      These table tents in Tisch Library seemed suddenly out of place as events such as Senior Week were thrown into uncertainty by the pandemic.
    - Students outside Tisch Library during power outage, 2020 March 11; MS269.000026; 847.7 Kilobytes
      To make matters more chaotic, the uphill portion of campus suffered a power outage the morning after the closure announcement was made. Classes that were scheduled to meet in Tisch Library congregated outside waiting for news. Professor Lee Edelman of the FMS Department is on the left side in green. Professor Jeffrey Berry of the Political Science Department is in the center of the photo with his back to the camera. Professor Berry dismissed us a few minutes after this photo was taken. His final message to us was "I didn't want to end class this way, but at least we're in the sunshine." I had two more classes scheduled for the following day; both were cancelled, bringing a swift end to the in-person classes of my junior year.
    - Public health signs posted in Tisch Library, 2020 March 11; MS269.000027; 1.2 Megabytes
      Public health messaging increased in the wake of the pandemic. These signs were posted in the Tisch Library G Level men's restroom.
    - Shattered bottle of Corona Extra outside Lewis Hall, 2020 March 11; MS269.000028; 5.4 Megabytes
      A shattered bottle of Corona Extra on the sidewalk outside Lewis Hall (Powder House side).